VICTOR RAMIREZ

Greenbrae, CA · (415) 299-4692

VRamirez75@gmail.com · www.linkedin.com/in/victor-hugo-ramirez-mids/ · vramirez-mids.github.io/

Self-driven and enthusiastic technologist with 10+ years of experience in software and cloud engineering roles. Excited to apply my new skills in artificial intelligence, machine learning, and data science to solve complex problems and increase financial investment returns

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Models: Machine Learning
- Languages: Java, C#, C++, Python (NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Keras)
- Database Systems: MySQL, Microsoft SQL, Postgres, NoSQL
- Data: Cleaning, Analysis, Modeling, Visualization
- Orchestration: Docker
- Research: Probability and Statistical Analysis
- Cloud: AWS, Azure
- Web: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap

EDUCATION

DECEMBER 2023

MASTER OF INFORMATION AND DATA SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, BERKELEY

3.80 GPA

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER SCIENCE, CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERISTYMONTEREY BAY

COURSES

INTRODUCTION TO DATA SCIENCE PROGRAMMING
RESEARCH DESIGN AND APPLICATIONS FOR DATA AND ANALYSIS
STATISTICS FOR DATA SCIENCE
FUNDAMENTALS OF DATA ENGINEERING
APPLIED MACHINE LEARNING

PROJECTS

Data Analysis - NFL Games

Exploratory data analysis of an NFL dataset using Python, NumPy, and Pandas tools. The project emphasizes data exploratory and descriptive analysis.

Statistical Analysis - Movie Revenue

Required selecting and developing a research question, curate the appropriate data, then conduct a statistical regression study.

Data Engineering - Store Location Recommendations

Explore using NoSQL databases Neo4j, MongoDB and Redis to recommend a store physical expansion.

Machine Learning – Understand Hate Crime

Leveraged machine learning to understand hate crime. Completed data cleaning, model creating and hyper tuning. Used linear regression to discover strong relationships.

EXPERIENCE

Moody's Analytics - San Francisco, CA & New York, NY Associate Director DevOps Architect

2009 - present

September 2015 – Present

- Cloud Providers: (Amazon Web Service and Azure)
 - Advise on systems design, feasibility, and cost studies and recommend costeffective cloud solutions
 - Advise software development teams on architecting and designing cloud infrastructure that safely and efficiently power the cloud environment
 - Coordinate strategy for on-premise to cloud migration and implementation best practices
 - Design and implement security model, VPC, Elastic IP for SCM tool on the cloud platform
 - Manage accurate communication of the status of ongoing work to stakeholders, including senior managers and executive management
 - Create online documentation to aid in knowledge management efforts within teams on cloud products and technologies
- Cyber Risk
 - Oversee company-wide information security standards
 - Coordinate data center sunsets during infrastructure migrations
- Manage software budgeting

Associate Director-Enterprise Risk Solutions

September 2014 - September 2015

- Managed release dates of software product
- Led all aspects of creating, installing, and updating Installers for software applications
- Implemented, maintained, troubleshot, and monitored the continuous integration system
- Created, maintained, and supported the build environments
- Improved the build and release automation
- Developed tools for customization and integration of software products
- Created and maintained process documentation for installation and maintenance of Moody's KMV suite of products

Streamline Solutions - San Rafael, CA Build/Install Engineer

January 2007 - October 2008

Leapfrog Enterprise - Emeryville, CA Project Engineer December 2001 - January 2007